HIDAMARI SO
（向阳庄）
-More please. -Of course.
-再来一碗 谢谢 -好的
Man, I can't get enough of your cooking.
天 你做的饭菜我真是吃不够
Once I start, I just can't stop.
只要开始就停不下来
Makes me feel energized for the following day.
第二天整个人活力满满
Or like the high-rise I gave up on wasn't just a dream.
甚至觉得我之前本已放弃的摩天大楼 并非只是梦想
-Here you are. -Thanks.
-请吧 -谢谢
Oh, yes.
对了
And remember to clean up afterwards.
吃完记得洗碗
COOKING - LAUNDRY CLEANING - TRASH
（做饭 洗衣 打扫 扔垃圾）
SAICHI AND MINAMI'S CHORE CHART
（财地和美波的家事分担表）
I've already placed my dishes in the sink.
我的碗已经放进洗碗槽了
And so…
那么…
I bid you good night.
晚安了
Good night.
晚安
That is good.
好吃
YAOKI COMMERCIAL DISTRICT
（八起商业街）
-Morning. -Good morning.
-早 -早上好
Mr. Nagase.
永濑前辈
-Hey.
-早
Good morning.
早上好
Isn't it lovely?
真好啊 是吧？
Store owners and volunteers working together to clean up the town.
各家店主和志愿者们一起打扫小街
What a great morning.
真是个美好的早上
Mr. Nagase.
永濑先生
-Thanks for your help before. -No problem.
-之前谢谢你帮忙 -不必客气
You really helped me out with the rent on my store.
我的店铺租金协商 你真是帮了大忙
I'm a realtor. Happy to help in any way.
我是房产中介 乐意为您提供任何帮助
-Micchan, come here. -Good morning.
-小实 快过来 -早
Micchan also needs some helping out.
其实呢 她也需要帮忙
-Won't you help her? -What's wrong?
-请你也帮帮她吧？ -怎么了？
Management has given me a warning about the common area in my building.
管理公司给我发了警告 关于我们大楼的公共区域
I'm good at handling that sort of thing.
我很擅长处理这种事
-I'll leave it to you. -Leave it to me.
-那就交给你了 -包在我身上
I really don't have time to be putting out fires right now.
我现在真没功夫帮别人灭火
I've gotta get more contracts and make my comeback as number one.
我得签下更多合同 重回销冠宝座
Nagase.
永濑
I see you putting in the late hours lately.
我看你最近都在加班
Thank you.
谢谢关心
So don't worry if you end up losing to Fujiwara in that race to get promoted.
所以就算在晋升竞争中输给了藤原 也别太担心
I haven't lost yet.
我还没输
I'm going out to speak with another landlord friend of mine.
我要去跟另一位地主朋友面谈 先走了
Hello. Kurosu here.
您好 我是黑须
Yes, I've been waiting for your call.
对 我一直在等您的电话
Thank you.
谢谢
-Yes. -Haven't you?
-对 -还没输吗？
You have a good eye!
您的眼光真好
So what if you don't get to become manager?
就算当不成科长又如何？
What?
啊？
Everyone loves you down at the commercial district.
商业街的大家都很喜欢永濑前辈
I envy you and your sales.
同为房产中介 我羡慕死了
Though it's not translating to results.
但这并不会产出什么结果
So what?
那又如何？
Yes.
好吧
I'm sure I mentioned that when going over the disclosure statement.
关于那点 我之前跟您说明重要事项时一定提过
You remember, right? Of course you do.
您还记得吧？您一定记得
You know I can't do anything about that now.
您知道我现在做不了什么
-Kurosu got another complaint? -Yes.
-黑须又被投诉了？ -对
He's getting a lot of them lately.
他最近经常被投诉
Of course he is.
那还用说
He's too pushy.
他太急于求成了
He's the one guy I need to beat.
他才是我需要打败的人
Yes, I do apologize.
行 很抱歉
Is everything all right?
没事吧？
They're just having a grumble.
没事 他们只是发发牢骚
Can't let a little thing like this get to me.
我可不能被这种小事影响
No, I mean,
我的意思是
you've been looking a bit pale recently.
您最近脸色有点苍白
How can you tell under all that tan?
他那么黑 你怎么看出来“苍白”的？
It's like there's a glow to your skin, but it's too bright.
就感觉…您的皮肤有种光泽 但亮得有些过头
Maybe I should win a big contract and head on over to the Ivory Coast to fix it.
也许我该签下一笔大单 再去象牙海岸晒回来
Just go to a regular tanning salon.
直接去普通的美黑沙龙就行了
LAVATORY
（洗手间）
Shit.
该死
STOMACH MEDICINE FOR TUMMY STRESS
（胃药 缓解胃部压力）
Damn it.
可恶
I can't believe that Mr. Popular is gaining on me.
不敢相信“人气先生”居然快赶上我了
On full commission, my sole existence is to make sales.
做为自由中介 我存在的唯一意义就是达成交易
FULL COMMISSION (NO BASE SALARY)
（自由中介 无底薪制）
If I'm not on top, I don't belong here.
如果不能当第一 这里就没有我一席之地
TOSAKA REAL ESTATE NO.1 IN THE AREA
（登坂不动产 本区第一）
Excuse me, we have a new client.
打扰一下 来新客户了
-I'll take it. -No.
-我去 -不
He's asking for Mr. Nagase.
他点名找永濑
Asking?
点名？
Yes.
对
He has a good eye!
他眼光真好
Excuse us.
打扰了
Hello.
打扰
I'm Saichi Nagase, as requested.
我是您要找的永濑财地
Hello, I'm Sakura Tsukishita.
您好 我是月下咲良
I'm Kento Tokage.
我是十影健人
Hello.
你们好
May I ask how it is you know me?
我能问问您是如何知道我的吗？
A man at Minerva Real Estate told me about you. Mr. Kamiki.
密涅瓦不动产的神木先生 向我推荐了您
Mr. Kamiki?
神木先生吗？
This has to be a trap.
一定是陷阱
Definitely a trap.
绝对是陷阱
THE HONEST REALTOR 2
电视剧名：正直不动产2
EP 8 OF 10 PERPETUAL CYCLE OF HELL
第8集：无限轮回地狱
I got a call asking if I'd like to invest in a studio apartment.
之前有人打电话问我 是否愿意考虑投资一套单房公寓
I've been in conversation with Minerva Real Estate so far.
目前为止 我一直在跟密涅瓦不动产谈
STUDIO INVESTMENT PURCHASE CONSULTATION
（投资公寓 购买咨询）
There's been a lot of cold calls for studio investments lately.
最近有很多推销投资公寓的电话
They say you can get started with very little money down.
他们会说 只需很少的本金即可入场
Studio apartments are certainly more affordable than detached houses
说起投资房产 单房公寓当然比独栋
in terms of investment properties.
更容易负担
Yes, and I know investing isn't easy.
对 我也知道投资并不简单
FUMIHIKO SHINOZAKI - EMPLOYEE AT A DISTRIBUTIONS COMPANY
（筱崎文彦 物流公司职员）
Three years ago,
其实三年前
I actually bought a new studio investment in Nishi-Kokubunji.
我已经在西国分寺 购入了一套全新的单房公寓
FIRST PROPERTY - PURCHASED NEW APARTMENT IN NISHI-KOKUBUNJI
（投资房产1 3年前在西国分寺购入的新公寓）
-Is that so? -Yes.
-这样啊？ -对
They said I could sublease to get a guaranteed rental income.
当时他们说我可以转租给不动产公司 获得有保障的租金收入
SUBLEASE AGENCY GUARANTEES RENT AS TENANT
（转租中介以承租人身份保证租金）
AND SUBLETS TO ANOTHER
（并转租给他人）
It was through a company called TBG Corporation,
当时找的是一家叫TBG的公司
but they went bankrupt two years ago.
但他们两年前破产了
It was a big deal.
那可是大事
Now I have no tenant…
现在我没了租客…
A FEW HOURS EARLIER
（数小时前）
MINERVA REAL ESTATE
（密涅瓦不动产）
…and I've been in the red for more than a year with no rental income.
…没有租金收入 我已经陷入赤字一年多了
Mr. Shinozaki, I think you should sell that property right away.
筱崎先生 我认为您应该立刻卖掉那处房产
While you may have bought it new,
虽然当初购入时是新房
in the past three years, it will have dropped in value by 70%.
但过去三年间 那里的市值已下跌了70%
Seventy percent?
70%？
You may have lost in one investment
这次投资您也许失败了
but you can make it back in another.
但您可以在下次投资中赚回来
He suggested I get another investment,
他建议我再买一套投资房
and he's recommending this one.
并推荐了这里
Jewel Yaoki?
八起明珠？
GREAT INVESTMENT 24-HOUR SECURITY - 18 MILLION
（绝佳投资房 24小时安保 1800万）
20 years old and 20 square meters.
房龄20年 面积20平米
Ten minutes on foot from Yaoki Station…
步行10分钟可达八起站
SECOND STUDIO PROPERTY PREVIOUSLY OWNED THROUGH KAMIKI
（投资房产2 神木推荐的二手房）
…and 18 million yen.
售价1800万
Is it too expensive for you?
对您来说价格太高吗？
I've already had one failed investment and I don't want to put my family out.
我已经投资失败了一次 不想再连累家人
I'm thinking I have to be careful.
我认为得谨慎行事
For this property…
这套公寓的话…
JEWEL YAOKI - 18 MILLION YEN 2.3% PER ANNUM
（八起明珠 1800万 年利率2.3%）
…you could take out a 30-year loan at 2.3% per annum
…您可以办理为期30年的贷款 年利率2.3%
with a repayment of 70,000 yen per month.
每月还款七万日元
If you were to rent it out for 100,000 yen a month,
如果能以每月十万的价格租出
that's a 30,000-yen profit right there.
那就有三万元的利润
And when you've paid off the loan,
等您还清贷款
the entire 100,000 yen in rental payments will be yours.
每月的十万租金将全额属于您
PROFIT - 100,000 YEN
（利润 十万日元）
If you're still having second thoughts,
如果您还拿不定主意
why not get a second opinion from another real estate agency?
不如去其他中介公司 问问第三者的看法吧？
What?
嗯？
I recommend Mr. Nagase, a realtor from Tosaka Real Estate.
我推荐登坂不动产的永濑先生
He's famous for being brutally honest.
他是出了名的直言不讳
He said that?
是吗？
JEWEL YAOKI
（八起明珠）
JEWEL YAOKI - PREVIOUSLY-OWNED STUDIO APARTMENT
（八起明珠 二手单房公寓）
It's an older building.
是栋老楼
Considering the low price keeps your up-front costs low,
考虑到价格低廉 可以降低您的前期成本
it certainly looks to be more suited for investment purposes.
确实更适合用来投资
So you think I should buy it?
那么 你们觉得我应该买下吗？
No. The exact opposite.
不 正相反
What?
嗯？
It's too much.
价格太高了
I'd say it's worth around 15 million.
我觉得也就值1500万左右
And I think it'd bring in 80,000 a month.
月租大概只能开到八万
So he was trying to pull the wool over my eyes?
所以他是想坑我吗？
Yes.
是的
KAMIKI'S EVALUATION 18 MILLION YEN - 100,000 YEN/MONTH IN RENT
（神木的估价 1800万 月租十万）
Even if you got it down to a reasonable price,
即便能以合理的价格买入
it's hard to tell whether you'd still be in the red or not.
今后是否能让您扭亏为盈也很难说
Nagase, no investment property can withstand that evaluation.
永濑先生 任何投资房产都经不起这样的评估
I mean, I wouldn't mind buying myself if the price was right.
如果价格合理 我自己都愿意买下来
Are you interested in investing?
你对投资有兴趣？
Passive income is a great use of time.
被动收入是对时间的合理利用
Yes, investing in studio apartments
确实 投资单房公寓
is an easy way to live the dream of living on passive income.
能轻松实现美梦 仅靠被动收入就能潇洒生活
As a realtor, I do recommend--
作为房产中介 我的确推荐…
Except,
然而
in reality, that dream is always a hideous nightmare.
在现实中 那种美梦往往是可怕的噩梦
What?
什么？
Investment properties aren't something for any old fop to dip his toes into.
投资房产可不是 随便什么工薪阶层都能涉足的
In reality, there are property taxes and management costs.
现实是 要考虑固定资产税和管理费
All those monthly expenses are sure to send anyone in the red.
每月的各种开销 无疑会让任何人陷入赤字
FOR SURE IN THE RED - PROPERTY TAXES AND MANAGEMENT FEES
（必然赤字 固定资产税 管理费）
If you want to be in the black,
如果想摆脱赤字
you need to constantly be on top of market prices and interest rates.
就得时刻关注市场价格和利率的变化
Sure, you might dip into the red,
但是 尽管可能陷入赤字
but it's an asset once the loan's paid off.
可只要还清贷款 那始终是你的资产啊
It can help support retirement.
能帮忙养老
Mr. Shinozaki.
筱崎先生
Can you say for sure that this property won't decline in value in 30 years' time?
您能确定 这房子三十年后不会贬值吗？
Mr. Kamiki said the data suggests it could go over 18 million.
神木先生说 数据表明今后的市值将超过1800万
You can't just accept him on face value.
您不能只听信他的一面之词
Numbers never lie, but you can exploit the way they're used.
数字的确不会说谎 但如何加以利用却有门道
Listen.
听我说
The real estate industry has its share of predatory hyenas
房地产行业中不乏掠食的鬣狗
who prey on ignorant civilians such as yourself.
您这样缺乏信息的普通人 正是他们的猎物
Every few years, an acquisition agent comes to buy your property on the cheap,
每隔几年 就会有中介来低价收购您的房产
then someone else comes to sell you another investment property.
然后又会有人 向您推销另一处投资房产
It's like a never-ending, perpetual cycle of hell!
就像个无限轮回的地狱
You're better off kissing that dream goodbye!
您还是赶紧跟那美梦说拜拜吧
Just what could Kamiki be planning with all this?
神木做这些到底有什么打算？
MINERVA REAL ESTATE
（密涅瓦不动产）
Mr. Tanaka was coming in at 5:00 p.m. tomorrow.
田中先生原定明天下午五点过来
He's just called asking to adjust it by one hour.
他刚打电话来调整了一小时
I was wondering when you'd show up.
我还在想你什么时候会来呢
Nagase.
永濑
What's this about Mr. Shinozaki and his studio investment?
筱崎先生和他的单房公寓 到底怎么回事？
I'm in the mood for a little bet.
我有兴致赌一把
A bet?
赌一把？
If I can get Mr. Shinozaki to purchase an inflated studio apartment, I win.
如果我能让筱崎先生 花高价买下一套单房公寓 就算我赢
If he doesn't buy, you win.
如果他不买 就算你赢
What do you think?
你觉得如何？
I think I'm a lucky man.
我觉得我运气很好
I managed to convince Mr. Shinozaki.
我已经说服了筱崎先生
I told him to sell his property in the red and to just cut his losses.
让他卖掉亏损的公寓 减少开支
You really are too soft.
你果然太心软
If I were you,
如果我是你
I would have shown him another property and got him to sign.
一定会带他看另一处房源 然后说服他签单
But I know you can't do that, so here's a little heads-up.
但我知道你做不到 所以我提醒你一句
I am number one in this industry.
我才是业内第一
Now it's my turn.
现在该我出招了
I have another little bet prepared.
我还准备了另一场小赌局
This one won't be as easy as Mr. Shinozaki.
这位可不会像筱崎那么好对付
Another one?
另一位？
-Hello. -Welcome back.
-你好 -欢迎回来
Has anyone asked for me?
有人来找过我吗？
Yes, they were looking for an investment property.
有 说是想找投资房源
Mr. Kurosu said he'd take it.
黑须先生说他会接待
-Kurosu? -Yes.
-黑须？ -对
CRADLE OGIKUBO MONTHLY INCOME OF 90,000 YEN
（荻洼摇篮 月入九万）
Make no mistake.
请看清楚
While it may be 20 million yen,
尽管要价两千万
mine is a much better bargain than that inflated Minerva property.
但我这套房源 绝对比密涅瓦那套虚高的房子划算
KEITO UNNO ELECTRICS FACTORY WORKER
（海野庆人 电气公司职员）
How much would the deposit be?
要交多少订金？
It's 10% on a property like this, so two million.
这种房子通常预付10% 也就是两百万
Doesn't that make it pretty much the same as Minerva's so-called inflated property?
那不就跟密涅瓦那套“虚高”的房子 一个价吗？
I'm already saddled with a studio apartment that's in the red.
我已经背了一套亏损的单房公寓
I've told you this.
我说过了
I need to keep my up-front costs low.
我得降低前期成本
UP-FRONT COSTS DEPOSIT, STAMP DUTY, ETC.
（前期成本 订金 印花税等）
Mr. Nagase is meant to be up-front. I should have gone with him.
听说永濑先生坦诚直率 我应该找他
I can still help you.
我还有个办法
Kurosu, what did you do?
黑须 你做了什么？
What's it to you?
与你何干？
That's no ordinary client you picked up.
你接手的那位可不是普通客人
He was sent by Kamiki from Minerva specifically to spite me.
他是神木为了针对我 故意从密涅瓦推荐来的
To spite you?
针对你？
Kamiki's done something,
神木已经采取了行动
and we need to stop that client from purchasing that property.
我们得阻止那位客人购买那套房子
Then you can rest assured.
那你大可放心
I'm such a great salesman
我是个优秀的销售
that I found him another more suitable property.
已经为他物色了一套更合适的房产
-You what? -So he's my client now.
-什么？ -他现在是我的客户了
Not yours, or Minerva's.
与你和密涅瓦都无关
I hope you didn't do anything underhanded.
希望你没做什么见不得人的事
Don't worry.
不用你操心
And quit butting in.
别再叽叽歪歪了
Kamiki.
神木
Looks like you're doing well selling all these studio investments.
看来你推销这些单房公寓的成绩不错
Yes, it is very fortunate.
是 非常幸运
Now we have all the funding we need.
现在我们所需的资金已经齐备
-Makes the next step even easier. -Yes.
-下一步将更加容易 -是
Now it's just Tosaka Real Estate blocking my view.
现在碍我眼的只有登坂不动产了
I've already thrown them off balance.
我已经让他们内部开始动摇了
It's time to take their greatest salesman down a notch.
是时候把他们最棒的销售拉下神坛了
You're really something, Kamiki.
神木先生真是厉害
How are you banging out one studio investment after another?
您究竟怎么做到的 竟能一套接一套地卖出单房公寓？
With this. It's a client list.
用这份客户名单
From TBG Corporation.
来自TBG公司
TBG CORPORATION CLIENT LIST
（TBG公司客户名单）
-TBG? -You've never heard of them?
-TBG？ -你们没听说过吗？
They went bankrupt after going into administration two years ago.
他们两年前因行政处分而破产
They specialized in studio apartments.
之前专攻的就是单房公寓
Why did they go under?
“行政处分” 为什么？
They used all manner of sales techniques, including intimidation and extortion.
他们为了销售 无所不用其极 手段包括恐吓和敲诈
At worst, they even forced people to buy at more than three times the market price.
最糟的是 他们甚至逼迫人们 以高于市价三倍的价格买入
And to ensure no one ever found out,
而且 为了确保不被发现
they only targeted the vulnerable.
他们专以弱者为目标
Once a fool, always a fool.
一次上当 次次上当
Where did you even get such a thing?
可是 您怎么会有这份名单？
From Mr. Ikaruga, the grandfather of TBG Corporation's high-handed methods.
TBG专横手段的祖师爷 可是咱们社长
I bought it off him for ten million.
这是我花了一千万从他手里买来的
Would you like to buy it?
你们有兴趣买下吗？
I could sell it for nine million.
我只收九百万
But only if you'll use it well.
除非你们能善加利用
Yes, thank you.
好的 谢谢
Goodbye.
再见
Who was that?
谁打的电话？
The realtor.
房产中介
Which one?
哪个中介？
From Tosaka Real Estate.
登坂不动产那个
He said I can call him anytime if I still have any concerns.
他说我如果还有任何顾虑 可以随时打给他
I agree. I think you should rip the plaster off now and sell.
嗯 我也觉得你应该 赶紧摆脱那烫手山芋
I've had it up to here with that investment.
那项投资真是让我受够了
MICHIKO SHINOZAKI MR. SHINOZAKI'S WIFE
（筱崎美智子 文彦之妻）
Don't worry about Kotono's school fees.
不用担心琴乃的学费
Yes, it's a private school.
的确 那是家私立学校
And yes, it's three times more expensive than public school.
学费也确实是公立学校的三倍
But I'll make sure we get by.
但我保证 咱们能撑过去
I wish she weren't just following her friends to this damned school.
哪有朋友去哪所学校 自己也非得去的？
SHUKEI UNIVERSITY HIGH SCHOOL 2024 PROSPECTUS
（秀庆大学附属高中 2024年入学简章）
Leave her be.
随她吧
She got into such a hard school with such a simple motive.
她为了这么单纯的理由 就考上了那么难考的学校
She's worked hard for it.
她付出了不少努力
We should support her.
我们应该支持她
Of course I support her.
我当然支持她
I'm back.
我回来了
KOTONO SHINOZAKI MR. SHINOZAKI'S DAUGHTER
（筱崎琴乃 文彦之女）
Welcome back, Kotono. Dinner will be ready soon.
琴乃 欢迎回来 晚饭马上好
Come on. Get changed.
快去换衣服吧
I don't need to be told.
不用你说
Hey, what's our annual income?
对了 咱们家的年收入有多少？
Why do you ask?
你问这个干什么？
You don't have to worry about any of that.
这些不用你操心
Fine.
行
JEWEL YAOKI TOSAKA - MINERVA
（八起明珠 登坂 密涅瓦）
Kotono?
琴乃？
You should be in bed.
快去睡觉
I'm just getting a drink.
我喝杯水就睡
Good night.
那么 晚安了
YAOKI COMMERCIAL DISTRICT
（八起商业街）
Good morning.
早上好
Shouldn't we be parting ways soon?
榎本小姐 咱们到前面就该分开走了吧？
What's this?
哟呵
Saichi is the type to be embarrassed by walking to work with his partner?
永濑是那种 羞于跟伴侣一起走路去上班的人吗？
I have absolutely no shame in walking with my partner.
我跟伴侣一起上班 一点都不害羞
It's just, we don't know who could be watching, so…
只是我们不确定会被谁看到…
No way.
不会吧
Make sure you come home early tonight.
今晚一定早点回来
I'll do my best.
我尽量
NUMBER OF CONTRACTS 61 CONTRACTS
（合同数 61笔）
Well done, Kurosu.
厉害啊 黑须
See what happens when I put my mind to it?
看到了吗？这就是我用心做的结果
Well, I have to yield sometimes, lest management start begrudging me.
我有时也得稍作让步 免得管理层开始嫉妒我
I haven't lost yet…
我还没输
Mr. Nagase.
永濑前辈
What?
嗯？
I know results are important to you,
我知道结果很重要
but you've been putting in so many long hours,
但永濑前辈 已经辛勤工作了这么长时间
so I think you deserve to go home early.
我觉得你理当早点回家
-What? -Miss Tsukishita, you have a client.
-嗯？ -月下小姐 有客人找你
Okay, thanks.
好的 谢谢
Thank you for giving up Mr. Unno as your client.
多谢你放弃了海野这位客户
I made a sale thanks to you.
多亏了你 我成交了一笔
I didn't give him up.
谈不上放弃
Mr. Unno was very pleased.
海野先生非常满意
Now he'll be able to make back what he lost
现在他能挽回损失了
through that infamous TBG Corporation scandal.
毕竟TBG出了那种丑闻
TBG?
TBG？
So he was also a victim of the TBG Corporation scandal?
他也是TBG丑闻的受害者吗？
I'm off to get lunch.
我要去吃午饭了
TBG Corporation went bankrupt two years ago.
TBG公司两年前破产了
Hello, Mr. Tosaka.
社长 您来了
-Hello. -Hello, sir.
-大家好 -社长好
Kurosu's in the lead right now?
现在黑须领先了？
All of our employees are doing their best through friendly competition.
是的 我们的员工 都在友好竞争 努力工作
MR. FUMIHIKO SHINOZAKI CALL
（筱崎文彦先生 呼叫）
Is that the guy with the studio investment?
是那个投资了单房公寓的人吗？
The one who nearly bought Jewel Yaoki?
差点买了八起明珠那位？
He might need reminding.
我可能该提醒他一下
Just leave it. It's not like he's our client anymore.
别管了 反正他已经 不是我们的客户了
Yes.
的确
Getting hung up on this
继续为这事投入心力
could just be falling for Kamiki's trap.
可能会正中神木下怀
Something wrong?
怎么了？
I was worried about a client who came seeking advice,
之前有位客户来寻求建议 我有些担心他
but it's all right.
不过没事了
I've got my eyes firmly set on being number one this month.
我已经下定了决心 这个月一定要成为销冠
Yes, well, we're not a charity.
好的 我们并非慈善机构
No, we're not.
是
Still, as a real estate agency, it's not just our clients propping us up.
不过呢 作为房产中介 我们依靠的不只是客户
We can only operate so long as the people are thriving.
只有大家都好 我们才会好
Remember that.
记住这点
Yes, sir.
是
Well, hello there, Mr. Shinozaki.
您好啊 筱崎先生
Mr. Kamiki?
神木先生？
Are you headed home?
您这是要回家吗？
Yes.
对
I wonder if I could have a moment of your time.
不知我能否占用您几分钟
Here.
请
Thank you.
谢谢
That studio apartment you recommended I purchase,
您之前推荐我买的单房公寓
I'd like to pass on it.
我想放弃
I was going to call and let you know.
我本打算打电话告诉您
I see.
这样吗？
My wife's sick of investing--
我妻子不想再投资…
Don't you get it, Mr. Shinozaki?
您还不明白吗 筱崎先生？
You, good sir,
您啊
are standing at a crossroads between victory and defeat.
正站在胜败的十字路口
What?
嗯？
Mr. Shinozaki.
筱崎先生
The moment of defeat, do you know when that is?
您知道哪一刻是失败的时刻吗？
Well…
这个嘛…
It's the minute you decide to give up.
就是您决定放弃的那一刻
Do you want everything to be for naught?
您想让一切都白费吗？
Of course not--
当然不是
Are you willing to pass up the chance of a lifetime to get it all back?
您想放弃千载难逢的 赢回一切的机会吗？
I have a chance…
机会…
I have him hooked.
他上钩了
This is the sunk cost effect.
这就是沉没成本效应
The psychological tendency of becoming emotionally attached to an investment.
一种在情感上 无法放弃投资的心理倾向
You can't give up, Mr. Shinozaki.
您不能放弃 筱崎先生
You can turn it around.
您可以扭亏为盈
I suppose I can.
我觉得也是
Next is the Dunning-Kruger effect.
接着就是邓宁克鲁格效应
The psychological tendency to overestimate one's own competency or abilities.
一种高估自己能力的心理倾向
Mr. Shinozaki.
筱崎先生
I do believe you are the sort of person who doesn't give up that easily.
我相信您是那种不会轻易放弃的人
You have a daughter going to a private high school this spring.
您女儿今年春季就将进入私立高中
Think of your family.
想想您的家人
This is your moment to put your foot down as head of the household.
这是您作为一家之主 当机立断的时刻
Are you in?
如何？
But you agreed we were done with investing?
可你明明同意了 我们不再搞投资了
If we give up now, we'll be left with nothing.
如果现在放弃 我们将一无所有
We don't have to do this.
我们没必要这样
Kotono will be going to college in three years.
可是再过三年 琴乃就要上大学
Yes, but we've already spoken about this.
我知道 可我们已经商量过了
We'll make sure we succeed this time.
我们这次投资一定要成功
You have a good eye!
您的眼光真好
Very well.
好的
As the number one sales rep, you can leave the rest to me.
我是王牌销售代表 您就放心交给我吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Here is the application form.
这是申请表
Mr. Nagase, you're not still vying with Mr. Kurosu, are you?
永濑前辈 你还在跟黑须较劲 是吧？
Of course I am.
当然
But I'm still worried about Mr. Shinozaki after that one meeting we had together.
但我们上次一起见过筱崎先生后 我现在仍有些担心他
Don't worry.
我理解
That's what makes you "you."
正因如此 你才是永濑前辈呀
Hello. Saichi Nagase from Tosaka Real Estate.
你好 我是登坂不动产的永濑财地
I'm going to Minerva.
我去密涅瓦了
I'll come with you.
我跟你一起去
Don't worry about it.
你就放心吧
I want to hear them too.
我也想听听他的说法
Mr. Nagase? What are you doing here?
永濑先生？您怎么来了？
I got a call from Kotono.
我接到了琴乃的电话
From Kotono?
琴乃？
How do you even know Mr. Nagase?
你怎么会认识永濑先生？
From before.
因为上次
Good night.
那么 晚安了
TOSAKA - NAGASE MINERVA - KAMIKI
（登坂 永濑 密涅瓦 神木）
Here.
这里
Thank you.
谢谢
It's almost time.
时间快到了
I've arranged a meeting regarding the Nishi-Kokubunji property.
关于西国分寺的房子 我已经预约了面谈
You're going to purchase the Jewel Yaoki, aren't you?
您想买入八起明珠的房子 是吧？
Kotono told me.
琴乃都告诉我了
I've thought it over.
我考虑过了
I'm sure you've thought long and hard.
我相信您一定经过了深思熟虑
But they say, "Once a fool, always a fool,"
但俗话说得好 “一次上当 次次上当”
and you, my friend, are a prime example of that!
而你 我的朋友 你就是典型的例子
In my opinion.
只是我的个人看法
It seems a client list belonging to TBG Corporation is making the rounds.
业内现在似乎流传着一份 TBG公司的客户名单
It's made its way into the hands of some morally corrupt people.
目前已经落入了 一些道德败坏的人手中
Mr. Shinozaki, it seems you've been unable to break free from your cycle of hell.
筱崎先生 看来您一直没能从轮回地狱中挣脱
No, but--
可是…
Kotono is scared this is all her fault for wanting to go to a private school.
琴乃担心 一切都要归咎于她想上私立学校
That's why she called me.
所以她给我打了电话
I…
我…
I've done some research…
我做了些研究
Families that earn less than 10 million yen per year
年收入少于一千万的家庭
get government-backed financial support for private school fees.
可以申请政府的私立高中补贴
FINANCIAL SUPPORT WEBSITE
（支援介绍网站）
FINANCIAL AID TO ENTER HIGH SCHOOL - SUPPORT FOR FEES
（高中入学资助 学费支援）
Applications open in April.
申请将于四月开放
Kotono.
琴乃
I told you. You don't have to worry about any of this.
我说过了 这些不用你操心
Just leave it to your father.
爸爸会处理好
You've got your priorities wrong!
您根本搞错了重点
What do you mean by wrong priorities?
“搞错重点”？什么意思？
Please. Let's hear it, Kotono.
琴乃小姐 请说来听听吧
I don't want
我…
to go to Shukei University High School just to be with my friends.
我想上秀庆高中 并不只是为了跟朋友们一起
I've heard their legal faculty is one of the best in the field…
我听说他们的法学院 在该领域名列前茅
and I'm thinking I'd like to be a lawyer in the future.
我以后想当律师
A lawyer?
嗯？
A lawyer? Why a lawyer all of a sudden?
律师？怎么突然想当律师？
It's not sudden. It's what I've always wanted.
不是突然 我一直想当律师
I want to help those who have been tricked by the bad guys.
我想帮助那些被坏人骗过的人
Because I know…
因为我知道
decent, hardworking people often find themselves in that situation.
正直勤劳的人经常陷入这种困境
You mean…
你是说…
So,
所以
Dad.
爸爸
You don't have to push so hard.
您不用这么逼自己
But how can I stand proud as your father like that?
可要是依靠政府资助 我还怎么自豪地做你父亲？
You've both done a great job at parenting.
两位在养育女儿方面已经做得很好
Just look at this noble young woman you've raised together.
瞧瞧你们培养的姑娘多么优秀
There's more to parenting than just offering financial support.
为人父母 能做的不只在于提供经济支持
Come on, honey.
是啊 亲爱的
I think we should listen to this man from Tosaka rather than Minerva.
我觉得比起密涅瓦 登坂不动产这位先生说得更在理
If you decide to go with me,
如果您决定把事情交给我
I'll make sure you get a good price for your Nishi-Kokubunji property.
我一定为您在西国分寺的公寓 争取一个好价
Kotono.
琴乃
What made you decide to call Mr. Nagase instead of Mr. Kamiki?
你为什么决定打给永濑先生 而不是神木先生？
Because I've heard of Mr. Nagase.
因为我听说过永濑先生
I'm a volunteer at the commercial district clean-up.
我是打扫商业街的志愿者
Mr. Nagase.
永濑先生
Thanks for your help before.
之前谢谢你帮忙
You really helped me out with the rent on my store.
我的店铺租金协商 你真是帮了大忙
Everyone's talking about him.
大家都在谈论他
They say Mr. Nagase from Tosaka Real Estate is honest and reliable.
都说登坂不动产的永濑先生正直可靠
Really?
这样啊？
You're going to leave everything with Mr. Nagase from Tosaka Real Estate?
您要把一切 交给登坂不动产的永濑先生？
No, it's fine.
不会 没关系
I understand, Mr. Shinozaki.
我理解 筱崎先生
I'm sorry I wasn't able to be of any help.
抱歉我没能帮您更多
Goodbye.
再见
Kamiki.
神木
I don't know what you're up to in the shadows,
我不知道你暗中有何图谋
but your crafty ways don't work on Tosaka Real Estate now.
但你的诡计现在对登坂不动产不灵了
If you want to compete, you have to play fair.
要想竞争 就得公平
No, wait. Please!
等等 拜托
Circumstances have changed. I can see clearly now.
情况变了 我现在看明白了
I'll bet I'd only lose money anyway.
我敢打赌 无论如何我都会赔钱
I don't want to live in fear any longer.
我不想再战战兢兢地活着
So…
所以
I'd like to pull out of our deal.
我想退出交易
I pulled all the strings to get you this contract.
我动用了各种人脉 才为您争取到这份合同
I told you it'd be impossible to break it after the fact!
我跟您说过 落子无悔
Circumstances
情况…
have changed.
变了
I'm back.
我回来了
Mr. Nagase.
永濑前辈
-Mr. Kurosu's in trouble. -What?
-黑须先生有麻烦了 -嗯？
He's just come back from negotiating with a client.
他刚跟一位客户协商回来
I shouldn't have taken Nagase's client.
我真不该抢永濑的客户
Now he wants to renege on the contract.
现在对方想毁约
Is that the studio investment property?
是单房投资公寓的事吗？
He says he doesn't need to invest anymore.
他说现在不需要投资了
What do you mean?
这是什么意思？
His wife was ill, and he wanted an income for her.
之前他的妻子病了 他想为她挣点医药费
But…
然而…
now she's dead.
她现在去世了
So, Mr. Unno's deposit is forfeit?
那么 海野先生的订金退不回去了？
Mr. Kurosu set the contract up with a token payment.
黑须先生签订合同时 只收取了象征性的中间金
Token payment?
中间金？
Let's break it down.
我来解释一下
A token payment is technically cash paid as part of the price
中间金通常是房价的一部分 在签订购房合同后
after the conclusion of a property contract.
用现金进行支付
LAST RESORT
（最后手段）
Executing a contract with a token payment instead of with a deposit
在执行合同时 收取象征性的中间金而非订金
is one way to reduce up-front costs.
是降低前期成本的一种方法
But as soon as that payment is made,
但一旦付款
it kicks off the contract and there is no way to back out.
合同就将生效 无法反悔
CONTRACT EXECUTED
（合同已生效）
SEVERE PENALTIES MAY APPLY FOR BACKING OUT
（难以解约 可能产生高额违约金）
While not illegal, it is a heavy-handed sales tactic not frequently used.
尽管并不违法 但仍是种并不常用的强硬销售策略
So it's not that he can't get out at all.
但也不是完全无法退出吧
But it requires both the buyer and the seller to agree,
但必须经由买卖双方同意
and there could be a hefty penalty.
而且可能产生高额违约金
The property sold for 20 million yen.
那套房子卖了两千万
That could fetch a four-million-yen penalty.
可能产生四百万的违约金
Four million?
四百万？
Has the seller even agreed to terminate the contract?
卖家同意解除合同了吗？
The settlement was to take place in three days.
原定三日后进行结算
I think they're saying it's too late now.
他们好像说现在已经来不及了
What are you going to do, Kurosu?
你打算怎么做呢 黑须？
I see you've been talking.
看来月下都告诉你们了
Let's work this out together.
咱们一起想办法吧
There's nothing to work out.
还能有什么办法？
I explained everything clear as day to Mr. Unno,
我早已把一切 跟海野先生解释得清清楚楚
and he never even told me about his wife.
他却根本没跟我说过他妻子的事
He reaps what he sows.
他要对自己的行为负责
Why can't he just keep the damn thing as an investment for himself?
他怎么就不能留下那公寓呢 自己用来投资不行吗？
Investment properties are difficult as it is.
投资房产并不容易
Is he even in a position to keep going?
而且他现在哪有精力继续下去？
It's not your problem.
不用你管
Mr. Kurosu.
黑须先生
Full commission means my job's always on the line.
做自由中介 意味着我随时有失业的风险
I'm ready for that!
我早有觉悟
I don't need rescuing by some hobby-hero.
我不需要什么业余英雄来拯救我
Have it your way.
随便你
How I wish I could just leave it at that,
真希望我能就这么一走了之
but you're in this mess because of this tiff between me and Kamiki.
可你卷入这事 是因为我和神木的较量
I'd be the worst kind of human if I just left you out to dry.
如果我见死不救 那真是太不地道了
We have three days until settlement.
结算之前 我们还有三天时间
We can find another buyer to replace Mr. Unno
我们要另找一位买家接替海野
and use that as leverage to get the seller to lessen the penalty.
并以此为筹码 让卖方减少违约金
Impossible.
根本不可能
I'll help.
我会帮你
Which property is it?
是哪处房源？
-Here. -Tsukishita, stop.
-这里 -月下 住手
It's this one.
是这个
I'll help too.
我也会帮忙
Tokage, you help until it's time to clock out.
十影 下班之前 你也来帮忙
Roger that.
好的
Use it, or don't. It's up to you.
用或不用 完全在你
Is this…
这难道是…
Fujiwara's client list?
藤原先生的客户名单？
Better get to it.
赶紧开始吧
Hello, how are you doing?
您好 近来可好？
-Tokage, start picking clients. -I'm from Tosaka Real Estate.
-十影 开始挑选客户吧 -我是登坂不动产的
-Sure thing. -Yes, it's been a while.
-当然 -对 好久没联系
Can you send me the additions?
能把追加名单发给我吗？
Already sent.
已经发了
No call again.
又不打电话
TACT - MINUS
（贴心度 扣分）
SAICHI NAGASE FUTURE HUSBAND GRADE
（永濑财地 未来丈夫评分表）
WORK - THREE
（工作 3分）
But he gets full points for dedication to his work.
但在敬业方面 他能得满分
WORK - FIVE
（工作 5分）
Concluded through a token payment, you say?
你是说签订合同时只收了中间金？
Very pushy of him.
他可真是急于求成
This Mr. Kurosu,
这位黑须先生
may have just been using you.
可能一直在利用您
He used me?
利用我？
He threw you under the bus
他牺牲了您
to improve his sales performance.
来提升他的业绩表现
HELPING YOU FIND A HOME
（协助您找到新家）
Really?
真的吗？
Thank you so much!
太感谢了
Yes!
太好了
I found a new buyer.
我找到新买家了
Well done, Kurosu!
好样的 黑须
Damn, he beat me to it.
可恶 被他领先了
I'll go and speak with the seller to cancel Mr. Unno's contract.
我去跟卖家谈谈 先取消海野的合同
Right.
好
I'll come with you.
我跟您一起去
Honestly, I think it'll help.
说实话 我觉得你去能帮上忙
Great.
好的
We'll be back.
那么 我们出发了
-Go get 'em! -Will do.
-去吧 -好
Hello. Mr. Nagase?
喂 永濑前辈？
It went perfectly.
进展非常顺利
Mr. Kurosu is a natural at negotiations.
黑须先生果然是天生的谈判专家
Really?
真的吗？
How'd it go?
如何？
Kurosu convinced the seller to be compassionate
黑须说服了卖家大发慈悲
and they agreed to completely waive the penalty.
同意完全免除违约金
Completely waived it?
完全免除？
I'll bet Kurosu's got a big grin on his face.
黑须脸上一定笑开了花吧
I mean…
说起来
If anything, he seems bashful.
要说他脸上有什么 其实是脸红
Get off that phone. Let's go.
赶紧挂了吧 我们走
Okay.
好的
We're about to go tell Mr. Unno the good news.
我们马上把好消息告诉海野先生
Mr. Unno! I have some great news for you.
海野先生 我有天大的好消息
Why are you so happy?
你为何这么兴高采烈？
Why the big smile?
为何笑这么开心？
Wait, listen to me! I have some good news.
等等 听我说 我有好消息
I don't want to hear it from a giant fraud like you!
我不想听你这种大骗子的说辞
-Don't push me. -What are you doing?
-别推我 -你们在干什么？
Mr. Kurosu!
黑须先生
Tsukishita?
月下？
What happened?
怎么了？
Mr. Kurosu from Tosaka Real Estate.
登坂不动产的黑须
A disgruntled client of his pushed him down the stairs.
有个心怀不满的客户 把他推下了楼梯
Really?
真的吗？
Seems it was out of desperation, as the guy had just lost his wife.
那人刚失去了妻子 可能生无可恋吧
It was the guy Kamiki was dealing with before.
就是神木先生之前接待过的那人
TBG CORPORATION - KEITO UNNO
（TBG公司 海野庆人）
Kamiki.
神木
Mr. Unno already felt like a loose cannon
当初我向海野先生推销时
the entire time I was making my pitch.
已经觉得他像个定时炸弹
I knew I wouldn't get any business from him,
我早知道无法跟他做成任何生意
but I figured I might aim him at Tosaka Real Estate.
但我想着 也许可以用他瞄准登坂不动产
You did this.
原来是你埋下的祸根
I'm just as surprised as you are.
我跟你一样吃惊
That said,
话虽如此
if only that realtor had turned his mind to Mr. Unno's family,
要是那位中介能多考虑下海野的家人
perhaps it needn't have come to this.
也许事不至此
YAOKI GENERAL HOSPITAL
（八起综合医院）
Hello.
您好
Are you all right?
您还好吗？
You didn't have to visit.
你们没必要来看我
How are you feeling?
您感觉如何？
Mr. Unno is so sorry for what he did.
海野先生为自己的行为深表歉意
He said he can't thank you enough.
他说谢您都来不及呢
He said he's glad you were able to fix the property issue for him,
他说很高兴您帮他解决了公寓的事
and he's grateful you aren't going to press charges.
也很感激您同意不起诉
It was only an accident.
没什么 意外而已
Solving problems without a hitch.
只想顺利解决问题
That's true full commission.
这才是真正的自由中介
Liar Nagase, at it again.
骗子永濑 又来了
But it's all right now.
但现在都没关系了
I'm going back to my hometown to take on the family inn.
我要回老家接手家里的旅馆
-What?
-嗯？
My parents have been on my back for me to take over for them.
我父母一直念叨着让我回去接替他们
You're kidding.
开什么玩笑
We all know you're a salesman at heart.
我们都知道你骨子里是个销售
I'll be putting my skills to use as the head innkeeper.
我要继续发挥我的才能 当好旅馆老板
I'm sorry. This was my fault.
抱歉 都怪我
Got you!
我赢了
I was number one right up until the very end.
我直到最后都是销冠
Now you'll never get the chance to beat me again.
现在你再也没有机会打败我了
Damn you!
真可恶
Well, we'll be off.
好了 我们走了
Nagase.
永濑
Don't you let Minerva beat you.
别让密涅瓦不动产打败你
Of course not.
当然不会
You really mean it?
真的吗？
Haven't you realized?
你还没发现吗？
I cannot tell a lie.
我啊 无法说谎
Do you think Kamiki planned for it all to get so out of hand?
事情如此失控 你觉得都是神木计划好的吗？
I wonder why he'd go that far.
不知道他为何会做到这种地步
At any rate, we can just keep doing our best.
无论如何 我们只能继续尽力而为
-Right. -Yes.
-对 -嗯
-Let's eat! -Let's eat.
-我开动了
-Welcome! -Hello.
-欢迎光临 -欢迎
So you're not at work. You're having dinner here.
原来你没在工作 而是在这里吃饭
You could have at least sent me a message.
至少可以给我发个短信吧
-How are you? -Good, thank you.
-你好吗？ -挺好的 谢谢
Work's only just settled down from today--
今天的工作才刚处理好…
I'll have a draft beer.
来杯生啤
One draft beer.
一杯生啤
Did something happen?
发生什么事了吗？
It's just that Minami, well,
因为美波小姐说…
she said to let her know whenever you showed up.
如果永濑你出现 让我们立刻通知她
Testing, testing.
测试
What? You're connected?
什么意思？你们能通话？
Enomoto here. Over.
我是榎本 完毕
What are you, a spy? Geez!
什么情况 间谍吗？天
Wow, that thing's huge.
哇 好大的家伙
So, can I ask you something?
话说 我能问你们一个问题吗？
Yes?
怎么？
Well, it's just,
就是…
I saw you guys walking to work together before--
我之前看到两位一起走路去上班…
Tsukishita. Stop.
月下 打住
No, I want to get it out in the open.
不 我想知道真相
Don't.
别
You're living together, aren't you?
你们两位同居了吧？
You're really asking me that?
这还用问吗？
Seriously?
真的吗？
It's not that we're living together--
不是同居…
Yes, we are currently cohabiting together.
对 我们现在同住一个屋檐下
This "wife" forced her way in and won't even let me have a good-night kiss!
这位“妻子”强行住进我家 却连一个晚安吻都不肯给我
How dare you put it like that?
你怎么敢这么说？
-Wife? -In inverted commas.
-妻子？ -打引号的
Really? Congratulations!
真的吗？恭喜啊
Finally!
终于等到了
It's still early days to be celebrating.
现在庆祝还为时尚早
He's only been short-listed.
他只是进入了最终考核名单
Still!
虽然但是
I'm so happy.
我太开心了
Damn, I want to be able to lie again.
该死 真希望我能再度说谎
NEXT EPISODE
（下集预告）
Tosaka Real Estate is headed down the drain.
登坂不动产正在走向衰落
This has nothing to do with you. Leave! How can we trust a realtor?
与你无关 出去 我们要怎么相信一个房产中介？
Wait! Don't go any further!
等等 别再往前走了
We'll come in first place.
我们绝对会成为第一名
Can you help them?
你能帮他吗？
You're the only one who can do it.
只有你能帮他
FINANCIAL SUPPORT FOR HIGH SCHOOL ADMISSION VARIES AROUND
（高中入学资助制度 在各地有所不同）
COUNTRY - PLEASE CONSULT WITH YOUR OWN MUNICIPALITY
（详情请咨询当地）
THE HONEST REALTOR 2 EP 8 - PERPETUAL CYCLE OF HELL
电视剧名：正直不动产2 第8集：无限轮回地狱